LUKAS KÖBIS

Address: University College, High Street, Oxford, OX1 4BH Email: lukas.koebis@gmail.com Tel: +44 7429 059825

PERSONAL STATEMENT

I'm a highly-motivated and committed undergraduate student. During the last years I was able to gain experience in different fields of software development.

Moreover, I improved and successfully demonstrated my problem-solving and analysing skills in various mathematics and computer science / programming competitions.

EDUCATION

09/2013 – 05/2017	University of Oxford, University College Bachelor of Arts (Mathematics and Computer Science) Prelims (1st year exams): 'Distinction' (80%)
08/2009 – 07/2013	Albert-Schweitzer-Gymnasium Erfurt, Germany specialised in mathematics and sciences German Abitur, mark 1.0 (best average mark)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

07/2013 – 08/2013	Software Engineering Internship at Nemetschek Vectorworks, Inc in Columbia, Maryland built a developer wiki (implemented MediaWiki plugins), developed GUI elements for the 2015 release, attended weekly developer meetings
08/2012 – 09/2012	Java and C++ Developer at plazz Entertainment AG in Erfurt, Germany worked on a cross platform game for Android and iOS (especially Android), attended meetings with customers and presented products

COMPUTER SKILLS

Programming: C++ (regular use in coding competitions), Java (Android), Python (scripting),
JavaScript (AngularJS, node.js), Scala (university), Haskell (university), Swift (basics)

PROJECTS

- QR-Code reader using OpenCV (high school project)
- Android game (https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.taimurlukas.metric2)
- currently working on a web platform to manage groups and events (http://hublist.co)

ACHIEVEMENTS AND AWARDS

- participant of the International Olympiad in Informatics (IOI) in Brisbane, Australia (top 4 in Germany)
- Mendeley API prize at the MLH Launch hackathon in London 2014
- member of the Oxford University team at the ACM International Collegiate Programming Contest (ICPC) Northwestern European Regional Contest 2013
- awardee at the final of the "National Computer Science Competition" in Kaiserslautern
- prize for the best interdisciplinary project in the "Youth researches" competition (implemented and evaluated a stock market simulation)
- recipient of the Konrad-Zuse medal awarded by Dr. Kurt Pauli

REFEREES

Available on request